什么味 你是在用大锅洗衣服吗
Ew. Are you doing laundry on the stove
就像古代那样
like in olden times?
我的天 咱家没钱了吗
Oh, my God. Are we poor?
我就知道老爸的魔术用品店会毁了我们
I knew Dad's magic shop would destroy us.
不 是我贝奇姑姑最喜欢的番茄汤
No, it is my Aunt Becky's favorite tomato soup,
我要带去给她
and I am bringing it to her
因为她中风了正在养病
because she's recovering from a stroke.
她是你们过去很怕的那个刻薄姑姑吗
Is she the mean one you guys used to be so scared of?
老天 是的 特别是你米奇尔舅舅
Oh, God, yes, especially Uncle Mitchell.
就像他是一头虚弱的瞪羚
It was like he was a weak gazelle
而她是一头饥饿又恐同的猎豹
and she was a hungry, homophobic cheetah.
无意冒犯 但那汤太难闻了
No offense, but that soup stinks.
哪有 挺好闻的
No, it smells fine.
有人在烧飞盘吗
Is someone burning Frisbees?
是汤
It's soup!
不 这可不是汤味
No, that's not it.
瞧瞧你穿得这么正式
Oh, look at you all dressed up.
跟我们一起去看米奇尔舅舅冒冷汗吗
Coming with us to watch Uncle Mitchell sweat?
不 阿尔文的爸爸从伦敦来了
No, Arvin's dad is in from London,
他想让我见见他
and he wants me to meet him.
等等
Hang on.
你没有宿醉
You're not hungover.
发型很保守 没露乳沟
Hair's conservative, no cleavage.
我的天 你想留个好印象
Oh, my God. You're trying to make a good impression.
你爱上他了
You're in love!
住口 我没有
Shut up. I am not.
我可说不准
Ohh, I don't know.
我看到你这次谈恋爱有多用心了
I see how hard you work at this relationship.
你起早去看足球赛
You woke up early to watch soccer
用的还是英式叫法
and you called it football.
冷静点
Oh, just calm down.
这才三个月
It's been three months,
而且人人都知道今年利物浦队特别顺
and everyone knows Liverpool is having a cracking good year.
尽管如此 见家长仍是恋爱一大里程碑
Still, meeting a parent is a major relationship milestone.
克莱尔 你让我有所期望了
Claire, you're getting my hopes up,
安迪留下的旧伤我还没疗好呢
and I still haven't recovered from Andy.
更别提迪兰了
And don't even get me started on Dylan.
我每次看到睡在车里的人都会忍不住怀念旧时
I get nostalgic every time I see someone sleeping in their car.
-你紧张吗 -不紧张
- You nervous? - No.
就算我紧张 我也早有准备
And even if I were, I've got it covered.
我从诺普带回了这些新贴纸
I've got these new stickers from NERP.
我们的最新产品
So, our latest product
是最惊人的科技大突破
is the most amazing scientific breakthrough --
贴纸
stickers!
你真是个天才
Oh, you're a genius.
我们生活的时代太棒了 我承受不住了
What an amazing time we live in. I can't.
这些贴纸能减压
So, they're designed to reduce stress
助你大胆地去追求辉煌
and to help you boldly pursue greatness
它能扰乱你大脑中理性的部分
by scrambling the rational part of the brain
让你不再自问"这样真的好吗"
that asks, "Does this seem right?"
总之 因为我不能用小白鼠做实验
Anyway, since I can't test on laboratory rats,
我需要你们来试用
I'm gonna need you guys to try them.
-好的 -好的
- Okay. - Okay.
等等 这里没人有起搏器
So, wait -- No one here has a pacemaker
或做律师的父母 对吗
or lawyer parents, right?
-没有 -没有
- No. - ?No.
那快试用起来吧
Then test away!
我去问问贝奇在哪间病房
I'll go see what room Becky's in,
或者我们可以摸摸哪个门把手阴气逼人
or we can just feel for which doorknob is cold.
菲尔 菲尔 你看到街对面有什么了吗
Phil, Phil. Did you see what's across the street?
-密室逃脱 -我看到了
- An escape room. - Oh, I did.
不 不去
No, we're not doing that.
绝对不去
No way in hell.
她连冰淇淋都要拒绝
She also said no to ice cream.
密室逃脱 那是什么
Escape room? What is that?
是个主题房间 他们把你锁在里面
Oh, it's a themed room that they lock you in,
然后你必须解开谜题和线索
and then you have to solve puzzles and clues
才能逃脱
to, um, you know, escape.
否则会被他们割掉手指吗
Or they cut off your finger?
什么 不
What? No.
-只是玩个好玩 -是的
- It's just for fun. - Yeah.
可那就没有高风险的刺激感了
Oh, but then that lowers the stakes.
好了 她在208号房 我们走
Okay. She's in Room 208. Let's go.
杰 你听到了吗
Jay, did you hear that
街对面有密室逃脱
there is an escape room across the street?
-我们不去 -为什么
- We're not doing that. - Why not?
因为你在高压情境下
Because when you get in a stressful situation,
就会开始大吼
you start to scream,
我可不想在上锁房间里体验那些
and I'm not taking that show into a locked room.
是的 这家伙连堵车超过五分钟
Yeah, and this one gets panicked if he's stuck in traffic
都会恐慌
for more than five minutes.
看来就咱俩去了
Guess it's just you and me.
绝对不去 亲爱的
Oh, hard pass, honey.
在密闭空间里
In a confined space,
你会像《飞天法宝》一样过度亢奋
you're just bouncing off the wall like Flubber.
大家都知道我和我妹妹贝奇不合
It's no secret my sister Becky and I have our differences.
他们九年没说过话了
They haven't talked in nine years.
她就像怪物一样
She's kind of a monster.
我只在我们的婚礼上见过她一次
I've only met her once, at our wedding.
想象一下 把杰身上所有最糟糕的缺点
Imagine if you took all of Jay's worst qualities
都塞进一套女士裤装里
and wrapped them in a pantsuit.
可我一听说她中风了
But as soon as I heard she had a stroke,
我知道我必须赶去她身边
I knew I had to rush to her side.
那是三周前的事
It happened three weeks ago.
在冰球季后赛进行到一半的时候中风
Right in the middle of hockey playoffs!
典型的贝奇扰人作风
Typical Becky!
她在那
Okay. There she is.
贝奇姑姑
Hi, Aunt Becky.
她好像睡着了
I think she's sleeping.
那副讨人厌嘴脸连睡着时都还在
With the same mean old puss on her face.
米奇尔 你为什么不去亲她一下
Hey, Mitchell. Why don't you give her a little kiss?
你去亲她
You give her a little kiss.
-不要 -是谁
- No. ?- Who's there?
我亲爱的家人们
My darling family.
你们来了
You came.
她的嘴哪里不对劲
Something's wrong with her mouth.
她在笑
She's smiling.
米奇尔 你变得真英俊
Mitchell, you've gotten so handsome.
你终于找到一个好女人了吗
Have you finally met a good woman?
不好意思 什么
I'm sorry. What?
你在逗我玩对吗 贝奇 你知道...
You're messing with me, right, Becky? You know that --
大伙 我能和你们聊两句吗
Hey, folks, can I speak with you for a second?
这就像我多年前出柜时一样
This is just like when I came out years ago.
她心里清楚得很
She knows what she's doing.
其实 她不清楚
Actually, she doesn't.
中风或许造成了贝奇的记忆混乱
The stroke may have scrambled some of Becky's memories.
这么说她不记得我出柜的事了
So she doesn't remember me coming out?
是的
Correct.
她现在以为你是直男
And now presumes you're straight.
她这想法我则是无从解释
That part I can't explain.
你有没有试过敲敲她
Have you tried popping her on the noggin?
她不是坏了的点唱机 方茨
She's not a jukebox, Fonzie.
再说 那也不管用
And besides, it doesn't work.
那只让我叔叔变得更糟了 他再也没醒来
It only made my uncle worse. He never woke up.
希望她的记忆之后能恢复
Well, hopefully her memory will return.
通常都是些小事能刺激回忆
Often, it's the little things that trigger recollection --
一种味道 一首歌 一张照片
a smell, a song, a picture,
甚至光靠家人的陪伴也有可能
even just her family.
谢谢您 非常感谢 医生
Thank you. Thank you so much, doctor.
你敲死了你叔叔吗
Did you kill your uncle?
她不记得我是同性恋
She doesn't remember I'm gay.
我知道 刚刚医生解释时我一直都在
Yeah, no, I know. I was here for the whole explanation.
这意味着我能再跟她出柜一次
This means I get to come out to her again.
第一次简直是灾难
It was a disaster the first time.
我下不定决心告诉她
I was-I was so wishy-washy about the whole thing
当我终于说出"我想我可能是同性恋"时
that when I finally said, "I-I think I might be gay,"
她说"好恶"
she said, "Ew."
你确定她说的不是"好啊"
Are you sure she didn't mean, "Ooh"?
不 之后她说了许多
No, no. It was followed up by a whole bunch of stuff
我让耶稣哭泣的话
about me making Jesus cry.
二十年来我一直后悔那一刻
For 20 years, I've regretted that moment,
而今天 我有机会重新好好做
and today, I get the chance to make it right.
或者你可以不刺激那个精神错乱的老女人
Or you could just leave a poor, old demented woman alone
不把她中风的事变成以你为中心
and not make her stroke all about you.
我到底为什么跟你说这些事
Why do I even bring you to these things?
贝奇姑姑 项链真漂亮
Well, Aunt Becky, what a necklace.
很漂亮不是吗
Isn't it lovely?
是我在列支敦斯登遇见的一位王子给我的
It was a gift from a prince I met in Liechtenstein.
真的吗
Really?
菲尔 那是我的项链
Phil, that is my necklace.
老爸和歌洛莉亚的婚礼时我借给她戴
I lent it to her for Dad and Gloria's wedding,
她从没还给我
and she never gave it back.
她说她弄丢了
She said she lost it.
克莱尔 她才经历了中风
Claire, the woman just had a stroke.
我毕业时 我妈送了我一条
When I graduated, my mother gave me
有特殊意义的项链
a very special necklace,
我拿去退款了才买的这条项链
which I returned so I could get that necklace.
我要拿回来
I'm getting it back.
-你要去哪 -我要去热汤
- Where are you going? - I'm going to heat up the soup.
或许汤味能让她恢复记忆
Maybe the smell will jog her memory.
她遭的罪还不够多吗
Hasn't she suffered enough?
我想这两个小家伙是最让我骄傲的
I guess I'm proudest of these two little guys here.
这是空间大师500 这是仙乐都
This is the Spacemaster 500, and this is the Xanadu --
普利切特衣柜的最新成员
newest additions to the Pritchett's Closets family.
普利切特衣柜是什么
What's Pritchett's Closets?
这该死的病连最美好的事都要毁了
This damn disease doesn't care what it destroys.
我知道有什么能帮你记起来
I know what would help you remember.
乔和曼尼给你录了"早日康复"视频
Joe and Manny made you a "Get well" video.
你知道吗
You know what?
我把手机忘在车里了
I forgot my cellphone in the car.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
谢谢你 迪迪
Oh, thank you, Dede.
深呼吸
Breathe.
你舒服吗 我能帮你做些什么
Are you comfortable? Can I help you with anything
不恶心的事吗
that's not disgusting?
我很好
I'm fine.
但我在想 今年夏天
But I was wondering if, this summer,
能不能把你的钓鱼木屋借给我
I could borrow your fishing cabin.
我的钓鱼木屋吗
My fishing cabin?
我爸有间钓鱼木屋 他保证过会留给我
My dad had a fishing cabin that he promised would go to me,
不过那个两面三刀的混蛋留给了我妹妹贝奇
but the double-crossing bastard left it to my sister Becky,
她也两面三刀
who's also a double-crosser.
现在她的记忆成了浆糊
Now that her memory is Swiss cheese,
我可以把我的木屋偷回来
I can steal my cabin back.
终于啊 好人胜利了
Finally, the good guy wins.
父亲
Hello, Father.
阿尔文 儿子
Arvin, my boy!
让我向你介绍
Uh, allow me to introduce to you...
海莉·邓菲
Haley Dunphy.
马尔科姆·费诺曼 幸会
Malcolm Fennerman. It is my pleasure.
做得好 儿子
Nicely done, son.
看到你找了个小姑娘[小屁股]我真高兴
Glad to see you've got yourself a little lass.
他说的是"小姑娘"
He said "lass."
对了 计划稍微有变
Oh, by the way, slight change in plan.
在最后一刻 你妈决定跟我一起来
at the last minute, your mum decided to join me on the trip.
-什么 -是的
- What? ?- Yes.
在布莱顿的那个周末后
I, um, can't go anywhere by myself
我不能独自去任何地方了
after that weekend in Brighton.
老妈要来 现在吗
Mum's coming here? Now?
一切还好吗
Is everything okay?
我还有喝一杯的时间吗
Is there time to get a drink?
恐怕没有 战斗人员就位
I'm afraid not. Man your battle stations.
你好
Hello.
我是艾丽斯·费诺曼博士
I am Dr. Iris Fennerman.
很高兴终于能见到
So nice to finally meet the woman
这位我儿子如此迷恋
with whom my son is so enamored
但我却没有任何认识的姑娘
and yet I know nothing about.
我只是一个很普通的美国姑娘
Well, I'm just your average American girl,
但幸好我比普通的美国姑娘轻非常多
although much thinner, thank God.
还有 我在诺普工作
Oh, also I work at NERP.
什么诺普
Nerp?
纳米电子研究项目的缩写
Nano Electronics Research Project.
我跟海莉是同事
Haley is a colleague.
但这是最高机密任务 不可言
It's very top-secret, though. Hush, hush.
我们刚才估计已经透露太多了
We probably already said too much.
马尔科姆 为什么还没位子
Malcolm, how is it we are not seated yet?
我不想...
Well, I didn't want to --
又选错桌子嘛
pi--pick the wrong table again.
别傻了 坐哪我都可以
Oh, don't be silly. I'd be happy anywhere.
什么时候开始的
Since when?
"纳米电子" 什么鬼
"Nano Electronics"? What was that?
求你啦 你就配合演出一下
Please, just play along.
你们在后面交头接耳什么呢
What's all that whispering back there?
没什么 妈 就聊科学的事
Uh, nothing, Mum. Just, um, science talk.
我实在待不住了
I had to get away.
普里契特家的人又开始发作了
It's getting way too Pritchett-y in there.
为什么来疗养院探望要搞那么复杂呢
Why can't they just let this be a fun nursing-home visit?
对啊 我们都来到里弗赛德了
Exactly. We're in Riverside.
我们应该尽情玩耍啊
We should be tearing it up.
我们去玩那个密室逃脱吧
Hey, let's go to that escape room.
我同意
I am in.
歌洛莉亚 我们要去玩密室逃脱
Hey, Gloria. We're going to the escape room.
-你想一起去吗 -感觉很有趣
- You want to come? - That sounds fun.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
杰好像需要我
I think Jay needs me.
他很难过
He's very sad. ?Oh.
别给她看那影片了
Forget the videos.
我们得让她想不起任何事
We have to keep her from remembering anything
我才能把我的钓鱼木屋拐回来
so I can nab her fishing cabin!
我突然有强烈想逃脱的冲动
I suddenly feel like escaping.
真庆幸我们决定去玩
I'm so glad we're doing this.
对啊 我也这么觉得
I know. Me, too.
等等 我们好像走错路了
Oh, well, I don't -- I don't think this is the way.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
不知道啊 我们沿着原路回去吧
I don't know. Let's just go back up.
惨了 锁上了
Oh, no. It's locked!
打电话叫人来开吧 我没带手机
Okay, call someone. I don't have a cellphone.
我收不到任何信号
Okay, well, I don't have any service.
我手机也没信号 两位 如果我们
I don't either. Guys, if we don't figure out
不快点想出办法离开这里
a way to get out of here soon,
那我们就来不及去玩密室逃脱了
we're never gonna make it to the escape room.
海莉 我知道你的工作是最高机密
Haley, I know your job is top secret,
但我真的对纳米科技十分着迷
but I'm so fascinated by nanotechnology --
就是能自我复制的机器人这类的
self-replicating robots and such.
我很有兴趣想听你对灰蛊的看法
I'd love to hear your insight into grey goo.
这题我能回答
Ooh, I can answer that.
那是我最爱的伏特加[灰雁牌]
It's my favorite vodka.
别再聊我了 我好喜欢你这西装外套啊
Enough about me. Um, I love your blazer.
你有像英国女皇一样养柯基犬吗
Do you have a corgi like the queen?
最近伦敦挺疯狂啊 对吧
Crazy times in London. Am I right?
我听说你们的... 伦敦大桥要垮下来
I hear that your, um, bridge is falling down,
垮下来[儿歌]
falling down.
海莉很明显是在开玩笑啦
Haley is obviously joking.
这个... 她身上有那种美式幽默
It's that -- It's that Yankee sense of humor, you know.
"吃我内裤[屎]吧"
"Eat my shorts."
"鸡儿硬啦"
"Schwing!"
你的手臂上面是什么
What is that on your arm?
是我手肘
Oh, it's my elbow.
真有趣
How delightful.
格兰芬多加10分
10 points for Gryffindor.
不是 是那个像贴纸的东西
No, the sticker-y thing.
其实这是我公司做的
Oh, it's actually from my work.
它能够把大脑的能量...
It channels the energy of your brain --
工作的事情是机密 还记得吗
Can't talk about that. Remember?
好吧 那来聊阿尔文
Fine. Then let's talk about Arvin.
你决定好接受博士后研究员职位了吗
Have you reached a decision on your research fellowship?
我决定不接受了
I have decided not to take it.
为什么 你不想去大型强子对撞机做研究吗
Why not? I mean, you'd be working on the CERN collider --
这可是一生难得的机会
It's the opportunity of a lifetime!
我只是不想浪费6个月的时间
Well, I don't feel like spending six months
待在瑞士的地底
underground in S-Switzerland.
拜托你别告诉我
Oh, please, don't tell me
你因为一个小姑娘而拒绝这机会
you're turning this down because of a girl.
听我说 这跟我一点关系都没有
Listen, I had nothing to do with this.
亲爱的 你关系可大了
Oh, darling, you have everything to do with this.
你向来就是遇见漂亮女生
You've always shown bad judgment
你就晕头转向 乱下决定
when it comes to a pretty girl.
-这话有失公允吧 -谢谢夸奖
- That's not fair. - Oh, thank you.
但好歹你以前从来没让她们
But at least you've never let one of them
影响到你的事业啊
get in the way of your career.
听我说 我才没有要影响到任何东西
Look, I'm not getting in the way of anything.
阿尔文压根没跟我提过
Arvin never told me about it,
就算他提了 我也不会懂
and even if he did, I wouldn't understand.
我工作的诺普是一个女演员开的网站
The NERP I work for is a website run by an actress
她觉得自己懂科学
who thinks she knows science
因为她曾经在007系列电影里
because, once in a James Bond movie,
演过一个核物理学家 梦娜·洛特博士
she played a nuclear physicist, Dr. Mona Lott.
海莉 你要去哪里
Haley! Where are you going?
有人邀请我到洗手间当研究员
Oh, I was offered a fellowship to the bathroom,
我决定接受这邀请
and I'm accepting it!
你还记得我在我的钓鱼木屋里
Do you remember that security system
安装的安保系统吗
I had installed in my fishing cabin?
我最后一次借你用时给了你密码
I gave you the code the last time I let you use it.
我现在忘了那密码了
I can't seem to recall it.
好吧 我想想
Well, okay. Let me think.
钓鱼木屋 那木屋
The cabin, the cabin.
那里风景好美
Oh. So pretty up there.
-我有老公吗 -去世了
- Did I have a husband? - ?Dead.
现在专心回忆那个密码
Now focus on the code and nothing else.
看看谁做了你最爱喝的汤啊
Hey, look who made you your favorite soup.
没有什么比熟悉的味道更能勾起记忆了
Nothing like a familiar smell to bring back memories.
-她吃过东西了 -是吗 我好像有点饿呢
- She ate. - I did? But I'm sort of hungry.
常言道 治感冒吃饱
Well, feed a cold,
-治中风得饿 把东西拿走
- starve a stroke. - Get that out of her.
你来我爸的婚礼时 我做了这个给你喝
I made this for you when you came to Dad's wedding.
我想起来了 你再婚了
?That's right. You got remarried
你娶了那个波多黎各女人
to that Puerto Rican woman.
你在那婚礼上好美啊
You looked so beautiful at that wedding --
你的裙子 你的鞋子 还有戴的珠宝
your dress, your shoes, the jewelry.
你过来 失陪一下
Come here a second. Excuse me.
你到底想干嘛
What the hell are you up to?
她偷走了我的项链
She stole my necklace.
所以你试图控制一个生病的女人
So you try to manipulate a sick woman
来得到你个人的利益吗
for your own personal agenda?
贝奇姑姑 你好啊
Aunt Becky, hi.
你还记得你来看我冰上舞蹈表演
You remember when you came to see me ice dance,
你说我看起来有点娘炮 我...
you said that I looked like a little sissy, well, I --
爸
Ow, Dad!
我真是以你们俩为耻啊
I am ashamed of the both of you.
里面躺着的人是我妹妹
That's my sister in there.
我差点就要失去她了
I almost lost her once.
我不想要再失...
I don't want to have to lose...
-天啊 -爸
- Oh, God. - ?Oh, Dad.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
我们很对不起
Uh, we're so sorry.
你说得对 我们太小心眼了
You're right. We're being petty.
是啊 克莱尔是想拿回项链
Well, Claire's is about a necklace
而我是想真实地活下去 不过我懂...
and mine's about living my truth, but I get --
我懂现在不是适当的时候
I get how this isn't the right time.
抱歉我情绪失控了
I'm sorry I snapped.
这真的很难熬
This is just hard, you know?
抱歉 你的妹妹说她想起来
Excuse me. Your sister said she remembers something
有关你的钓鱼小屋安保密码的事情
about the security code to your fishing cabin?
我怎么记得那是她的钓鱼小屋
Well, I -- I thought it was her fishing cabin?
天啊 她现在记成是你的
Oh, my God, and she thinks it's yours,
你不想要她重新想起来
and you don't want her to remember it.
对啦对啦 你们说得对
Okay, fine. You're right.
但在你们开始指责我之前
But before you start throwing stones,
或许你们应该扪心自...
maybe look deep into your own...
-什么 爸 -什么 不行
- What? Dad. ?- What? No.
-爸 爸 -开门 开门 别关门啊
- Dad. Dad. - No. No, no, no, no, no, no.
好的 我们不用恐慌的吧
All right. We shouldn't be panicking, right?
不用 当然不需要
No, of course not.
肯定有无数种我们可以离开这里的方法
There's got to be a million ways out of here.
那里有保安摄像机
There's a security camera.
别 别啊 是旧的早坏了
Oh, no. No, no. It's old and broke.
来人啊 我们被反锁在这里了
Hey! Hey! We're stuck in here!
歌洛莉亚 你这招五分钟前就没用
Gloria. ?Gloria, that didn't work five minutes ago,
在十分钟前也没管用
and it didn't work 10 minutes ago.
为什么没人听到我们
Why can't they hear me?
这通风管肯定得通到别地方啊
This vent has to go somewhere.
歌洛莉亚·玛丽亚·拉米瑞兹·迪尔加多·普里契特
Gloria Maria Ramirez Delgado Pritchett,
-你就是个天才 -我知道
- you are a genius. - I know.
-推我一把 -不 应该是我
- Give me a boost. - No, it should be me.
行吧 歌洛莉亚 你推小卡吧
Right. Gloria, give Cam a boost.
不是啦 我的意思是我来推你
No, I mean, I should give you a boost.
这样能行
Process works.
我们踩那个箱子不行吗
Why don't we use that trunk?
你看 我们几个能相辅相成
See?! We just make each other better.
好了 椅子 椅子 谁需要普里契特那帮人啊
Right, chair, chair. Who needs Pritchetts?!
我来扶着
I'll steady it.
再次谢谢你
Thank you again.
好了 好了 格栅[很棒]
Okay. Okay, grate.
你才棒呢
You're great.
你是说这个格栅啊
Oh, this grate.
我拿住了 好的
I got it. All right.
学电影《虎胆龙威》那样爬吧
Let's "Die Hard" this puppy.
那是我的肩膀
That's my shoulder.
好了 进去吧
Okay, in we go.
好了 菲尔 爬一段就敲几下
All right, now, Phil, every couple of feet, knock
这样我们知道你到哪里了
so we know where you are.
没问题
Got it.
-怎么样 -两位 我好像看到有开口
- Okay? - Guys, I think I see an opening.
我们有救了
We're saved.
呜呼 太好啦 要命啦
Yippie-ki-yay, mother-- oh, dear God.
菲尔 菲尔 菲尔
Phil? Phil? ?Phil?!
好消息 两位 我看到两个人
Good news, guys. I see two people.
或许我可以... 原来是你们啊
Maybe I can get a -- Oh, it's you.
-你好 -海莉 对不起
- Hello? - Haley, I'm sorry.
你生气跑出餐厅是合理的
You had every right to run out of the restaurant.
我也是见过不少极品男友的人
You know, I've put up with a lot from boyfriends --
睡车上 爱打游戏 有老婆
futons, video games, wives.
而你居然觉得我丢你人
But you were ashamed of me.
我妈就是个爱品头论足的势利眼
My mother is a judgmental snob!
我希望她能喜欢你嘛
I-I wanted her to like you.
我知道我... 我知道我完全做错了
I know I just -- I handled it all wrong.
但求你回来吧
But please come back.
不要 你让我觉得自己好差
No! You made me feel bad about myself,
而我应该被人更好地对待
and I deserve better than that, okay?
所以你就去瑞士吧
So just go to Switzerland
不就去坐在个大东西 比如瑞士巧克力里
and sit in a big thing of, like, Swiss chocolate
然后唱瑞士山歌吧
and -- and yodel, okay?
我们到此为止吧
We're done.
天啊
Oh, my God.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
为什么你们都有口音啊
Why do you all have accents?
怎么回事
What happened?
你晕过去了
You passed out.
你手臂上的贴纸
Those stickers on your arms
上面满载了各式各样的化学物质
are loaded with all sorts of chemicals.
我们打给你的紧急联络人了
We called your emergency contacts.
你的男朋友来了
Your boyfriend's here.
还好吗 小美女
Hey, sunshine.
安迪 你... 你从犹他州大老远来了吗
Andy? You -- You came all the way from Utah?
没有啦 我刚好回来上一个自助研讨会
Oh, no. I was in town for a self-help seminar --
"如何在正确的时间出现在正确的地点"
"How To Be In The Right Place at the Right Time."
天啊 还真的有用
Holy cow. It's working.
天啊 我估计你的名字在我手机上
Oh, gosh, I guess your name must still be in my phone
还显示是我紧急联络人
as my emergency contact.
我都是输入我男友的名字免得被爸妈训
I use boyfriends to avoid lectures from my parents.
我可不想那天在墨西哥的监狱醒来
I don't want to wake up in a Tijuana prison
然后还得听他们说"你被禁足了"
and them be all like, "You're grounded."
我很庆幸我能来这里陪你
I'm just glad I could be here.
安迪 我有件事得告诉你
Andy, um, I have to tell you something.
我也真的真的很抱歉
And I'm really, really sorry,
但我现在有对象了
but I'm seeing someone.
-真的吗 -真的
- Really? - ?Yeah.
赞啦
Yes! Whoo-hoo!
真是谢天谢地啊
Oh, thank goodness.
我也有对象了 我只是不知道怎么开口
Me, too. I just didn't know how to tell you,
尤其是在以为你会死的时候
especially if you were dying.
她是个湖人女孩
Oh. ?She's a laker girl.
她是湖人队的拉拉队员啊 不错啊
Oh, wow. A cheerleader. Nice.
不是不是不是
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
约瑟芬在大盐湖帮人的船清除藤壶
Josephine scrapes barnacles off boats in the Great Salt Lake.
我们称呼她们为湖人女孩
We call them laker girls.
不过她们在犹他州也算是性感象征呢
But they are kind of sex symbols in Utah.
所以是谁有幸得到你啊
So, who is the lucky guy?
我跟他的感情现在有点一团乱
Well, it's a bit of a mess right now,
不过他是个教授还是个天体物理学家
but, um, he is a professor and an astrophysicist.
他是个真正的天才
He's a -- a legit genius.
海莉 我尽快赶来了
Haley! I came as soon as I heard.
其实这不是真的
Actually, that's not true.
我中间去吃了个炸玉米饼
I stopped for tacos.
不是他
Not him.
有人有汤匙吗
Anybody got a spoon?
我们可以学《肖申克的救赎》挖洞逃
We could "Shawshank" this thing.
你学《虎胆龙威》时也没多成功啊
It didn't go so well when you "Die Hard"-ed it.
好吧 我先声明
Okay. Full disclosure.
当我感到没人支持时 我大脑会停工
If I don't feel supported, I tend to shut down.
好的
Okay.
我... 我觉得有点喘不过气
I'm, um -- I'm getting stuffy.
这里是不是越来越闷了
Is -- Is it getting stuffy in here?
加把劲啊 这里肯定有东西
Come on. There's got to be something in this place
能帮助我们出去
that can help us.
快看 有电话
Hey, hey! Whoa, whoa! A phone!
这里面有插口吗
Is there a plug around here?
快来找 这里一定有插口
Somebody -- There's got to be a plug.
我们快来找插口
Everybody look for a plug!
如果没有人来这下面怎么办
What if nobody looks down here?!
我们怎么活下去
You know, how are we gonna survive?
我车上有能量条
I -- I had a protein bar in my car.
我为什么没随身带着呢
I don't know why I didn't bring it in.
肯定有插口
Got to be a plug.
这里没有插口
There is no plug!
能量棒里有花生酱跟20克的蛋白质
It was peanut butter and 20 grams of protein.
两位 如果真到了那时候 我说认真的
Guys, if it comes to it, and I mean this --
我希望你们俩吃了我活下去
I want you guys to eat me.
就像多年来那几次电梯故障
As I told you before, in those elevators
或者是堵车时我回答你的答案一样
and in the traffic jam years ago,
我才不会吃掉你
I am not going to eat you.
你现在这么说 但我们可能逃不出去
Okay, you say that now, but we may not get out of here,
到时候我们可能就得下艰难的决定了
and we may have to make some hard decisions.
看看我们的样子
Look what is happening!
他们完全说中了我们现在的模样
Exactly what they said is going to happen!
你过度亢奋而你在恐慌
You're bouncing off the walls and you're panicking!
而你也在大吼大叫
And you're yelling.
我才没有呢
No, I'm not.
克莱尔或许说对了
Look, Claire may be right.
我现在可能精神涣散
I may be unfocused, but --
但换做是她 她也不会表现多好
but she wouldn't be doing any better.
她肯定会精神过度集中在一些白痴小事
She'd be hyper-focused on something stupid like --
比如..."为什么那些线
like -- like, "Why aren't the wires connected
都没有接到保安摄像头上"
to that security camera?"
对啊 为什么都没接上
Yeah, why aren't they connected?
等等 她说到点子上了
Wait. She's onto something.
那些线是被人剪断的
The wires are cut.
为什么会有人要剪斷位在地下室的
Why would someone cut the wires to a security camera
保安摄像头的线路啊
in a basement room?
米奇尔这种时候可能就会想出阴谋论
Well, Mitchell would have some conspiracy theory
觉得这里可能是别人进行非法事务的地方
that this is where the staff does illicit behaviors.
肯定是了
That's what it is.
打从我们一到这里我就一直闻到大麻味
I have been smelling marijuana since I got here!
我来扶着歌洛莉亚
I got Gloria.
天啊 她就像个缉毒局嗅毒犬
My God, she's like a DEA dog.
味道是从...
It's coming from...
这下好了 我们有了大麻 但是没打火机
Great. Now we have marijuana and no lighter
只有这把白痴钥匙
and just this stupid key.
我仿佛能听到杰在说
I can hear Jay saying,
"可能那就是门的钥匙呢 傻子"
"Maybe that key opens the door, dummy."
他们绝对不能知道自己比我们聪明多少
They can never know how much smarter they are than us.
绝对不
Never.
你能想起来的 贝奇
You got this, Becky. ?Mm-hmm.
你走进木屋 你按了按钮
You walk in the cabin, you push those buttons.
按了发出 滴 滴 滴 滴
They go beep, boop, boop, boop.
是哪些数字
What are the numbers?
周
Weeks!
我中风三周了
Since I've had my stroke,
这是你第一次来看我
and this is the first time you come and visit,
而你心里只想着那间傻逼木屋
and all you can care about is that stupid cabin.
等等 不 什么
Wait. No, what?
我的大脑才没事
My brain is fine!
但是医生说...
But the doctor --
那是隔壁病房的弗莱德
That's Fred from next door.
他曾经在肥皂剧里演过一次医生
He played a doctor on a soap opera once,
就留下了那件白大褂
and he kept the coat.
但当时是冰球季后赛嘛
But it was hockey playoffs.
太谢谢你了 谢谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
贝奇姑姑 真的很对不起
Oh, Aunt Becky, I'm so sorry.
我刚才跟列支敦士登的王子通完电话
I just got off the phone with the Prince of Liechtenstein.
他现在有很严重的财务困境
He's having some terrible financial troubles.
他要你把那条项链还给他
He's gonna need the necklace back.
这是为了让国民能温饱
You know, to feed his people.
省省吧 小公主
Save it, princess.
她的记忆根本没出问题
There's nothing wrong with her memory.
她就是在整我们
She was messing with us.
很贱吧
Mean, huh?
太坏了
Horrible.
那是我的项链 还给我
That's my necklace. Give it back.
等你把我车子那道
Not until you fix the dent
你高中时留下的坑修好在说
you put in my car in high school...
那坑现在还在呢
which is still there!
你还留着那台车啊
You kept the Bonneville?
你的口气听不出有否认是凶手啊
That certainly doesn't sound like a denial.
这条项链我要留下
I'm keeping the necklace. Ugh.
那你也还记得我的事吗
So you also know about me too, then?
你怎么了
What about you?
天啊 这要来了
Oh, God. This is happening.
我... 我... 其实我...
Um, I-I, um -- I -- so I --
有话快说
Spit it out.
我来不是想要拿走你任何东西
Uh, I'm not here to take anything from you.
我来是想要当真实的自己
I'm here to be my true self.
-真是要命了 -而真实的我...
- Oh, for God's sake. - And my true self is --
贝奇姑姑
Aunt Becky!
我是个...
I am...
律师
a lawyer.
律师吗
A lawyer?
好恶
Ew.
这下两件事都被她说"好恶"了
Well, that's "Ew" for two.
她情况怎么样了
How is she?
不好 能完全康复
Not good. Full recovery.
迪兰 很抱歉你被通知来
Dylan, I'm sorry you got called.
或许你没从电话里删除掉我
Well, maybe you didn't delete me from your phone
是因为你还没从心里删除掉我
because you didn't delete me from your heart.
或者是我忘了删
Or I just forgot.
随你嘴硬 海莉 我结婚了
Right. I'm married, Haley,
我跟她只爱彼此 你得向前看了
and we're monotonous. You got to move on.
真希望我还在昏迷
Ugh. I wish I was still in my coma.
她有男朋友了 不是我
She has a boyfriend. Not me.
我有女朋友了
I have a girlfriend.
她是个湖人女孩
She's a laker girl.
藤壶清除员吗 性感啊
Oh, barnacle scraper? Hot.
邓菲小姐 这男人也说是你的男朋友
Miss Dunphy? This man also says he's your boyfriend.
我是哪里没做对啊
What am I doing wrong?
海莉 你没事吧
Haley. Are you okay?
我好担心你
I've been so worried.
谁... 这都是谁
Who's -- Who's this?
我是在你之前的男友 而他还在我之前
I'm the guy before you, and he's the guy before me.
你们好
Cheers.
海莉
Um, Haley.
我们得聊聊今天发生的事
We need to talk about what happened.
你搞砸了 这就是发生的事
You screwed up. That's what happened.
对对对 永远都是我们错
Right. It's always us.
我们说好了那只大肚猪一起养
We go halfsies on a pot-bellied pig,
结果当它开始口吐白沫以及把你老妈
and suddenly it's all mine when it's frothing at the mouth
逼到洗衣房角落时 就是我的猪了
and corners your mom in the laundry room.
他撒谎瞒他爸妈我做的工作
Hey, he lied to his parents about my job
因为我让他觉得丢脸了
because he's ashamed of me.
不不 不是的 我没觉得你让我丢脸
Oh, no, no. No. I'm not ashamed of you.
我只是一下子手足无措
I just panicked.
在你走了之后 我跟我妈坦白了你的事
Look, right after you left, I told Mum the truth about you
说了你的工作 以及如果我想拒绝一个工作
and your job and that if I want to turn down a job
好跟你在一起
to be with you,
那也是我的权利
then that's my right.
无所谓了 我们之间就这样吧
Well, it doesn't matter. This isn't working out anyways.
-又来啦 -真的是
- There it is. - Totally.
他们在说什么
What are they talking about?
他们觉得我是在害怕
Ugh, they think that I'm freaking out
因为你选我而没选好工作
because you chose me over that great job,
这表示你对我感情非常浓烈
which means that you have big feelings for me,
这逼得我也得正视对你的感情
which forces me to look at my feelings for you.
然后呢
And?
然后...
And...
我也对你有很浓烈的感情
I have big feelings, too.
你有吗
You do?
当然有啊
Yes.
-说出来吧 -你闭嘴
- Say it. - ?Shut up.
我来说吧
I'll say it.
海莉 我爱你
Haley, I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我一接到电话就立刻赶来了
I came as soon as I got the call.
她的病情预报是怎么样
What's her forecast?
走啊 走走走
Go, go, go, go, go!
拿到手了吗 我给了她一个道别拥抱
Did you get it? I gave her a hug goodbye,
配合我熟练地手法 在第三次尝试之后...
used my sleight-of-hand, and on the third try --
用我的魔术来做这种事感觉好坏啊
I feel so naughty using my magic like that.
我爱死你了 宝贝
I love you, baby.
你前男朋友们警告过我你是这样的女人
Your old boyfriends warned me you were like this.
把项链还我
Give me that necklace.
她追上来啦
She's coming
把项链还我
Give me that necklace.
走走走
Go go go.
我们来试试车吧
Watch what this bad boy can do.